{
    "1": {"question": "What factors influence hair growth?", "answer": "Genetics, strength of your integumentary system (skin and hair), diet and medications"},
    "2": {"question": "On average, how fast does hair grow", "answer": "Hair grows about Â½ inch per month"},
    "3": {"question": "What protein do nails and skin share?", "answer": "Protein keratin"},
    "4": {"question": "What are the 3 layers of the hair called?", "answer": "Cuticle - outer layer, cortex - middle layer and the medulla - inner layer"},
    "5": {"question": "What layer of the hair holds the bonds?", "answer": "The cortex - strength, elasticity bonds and proteins, altered during chemical process"},
    "6": {"question": "What is a patch test?", "answer": "Patch tests check for allergies, place a drop of chemical on inside of elbow or behind ear of client and check reaction after 24-48hrs"},
    "7": {"question": "What is a porosity test?", "answer": "Porosity is the hair's ability to obtain moisture and tested by holding a few strands of hair with tension and running your fingers across them"},
    "8": {"question": "What are the 3 stages of hair growth?", "answer": "Cycle starts with anagen, followed by catagen then telogen"},
    "9": {"question": "On average, how many hairs are shed daily?", "answer": "Body sheds 50 to 100 hairs a day"},
    "10": {"question": "What is the term for hair loss?", "answer": "Alopecia"},
    "11": {"question": "Which type of alopecia comes from old age?", "answer": "Alopecia Senilis"},
    "12": {"question": "Which type of alopecia comes from your genes?", "answer": "Androgenic Alopecia"},
    "13": {"question": "Name some surgical procedures used to correct hair loss.", "answer": "Hair transplants, scalp reductions and flap surgery"},
    "14": {"question": "Name a pro and a con of using synthetic hair.", "answer": "Pro: Ability to accept chemicals better than the other types of hair. Con: Does not take well to chemicals and also melts when too much heat is applied, client's actual texture and color are extremely hard to match"},
    "15": {"question": "What is the difference between epilators and depilators?", "answer": "Epilators pull the entire hair out of the hair follicle: wax, depilators dissolve the hair at the hair bulb: nair. Depilators dissolve and epilators (epilators) pull."},
    "16": {"question": "What are the 2 methods to rest at the shampoo bowl?", "answer": "Recline and incline"},
    "17": {"question": "What is the purpose of conditioner?", "answer": "Conditioners restore moisture, oil and proteins to the hair and scalp"},
    "18": {"question": "What type of tape is used when applying a hairpiece?", "answer": "Spirit gum is a two-sided tape that helps keep the hairpiece on the skin without harming the skin or the hairpiece."},
    "19": {"question": "What is a styling block?", "answer": "A styling block is a device used to simulate a person's head for wig purposes."}
}
